Guide to the Norman Rubington Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Norman Rubington papers
1951-1990
YCAL MSS 643
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.34
(9 boxes) + 8 cold storage items
The Norman Rubington Papers contain the writings, films, and collages of Norman Rubington.
Rubington
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Norman Rubington, 2000-2001.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 7-14 (motion picture film): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Norman Rubington
Norman Rubington, American author, painter, poet, filmmaker, and collagist. He published several novels under the name Akbar Del Piombo. Rubington was born in New Haven, Connecticut in 1921 and died in New York City in January 1991.
Scope and Contents
The Norman Rubington Papers contain the writings, films, and collages of Norman Rubington.
Arrangement
Organized into eight groupings: I. November 2000 Acquisition. II. January 2001 Acquisition. III. January 2001 Acquisition. IV. February 2001 Acquisition. V. April 2001 Acquisition. VI. May 2001 Acquisition. VII. July 2001 Acquisition. VIII. May 2001 Acquisition.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Motion pictures (visual works); Artists -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Novelists -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Del Piombo, Akbar, 1921-1991
- November 2000 Acquisition, undated; 1; 0.42; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 81
  - Untitled typescript draft, corrected (Box 1)
  - "Roy" typescript draft, corrected (Box 1)
    Writings by Akbar del Piombo
  - Poems, typescript drafts, corrected, 3 (Box 1)
- January 2001 Acquisition, undated; 2; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 97
  - "New York via Pluto" by Akbar del Piombo (Box 2)
  - Poems, typescript drafts, corrected (Box 2)
  - Genesis Fireball, typescript drafts, corrected, 3 (Box 2)
- January 2001 Acquisition, undated; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 98
  - Is God French?, typescript drafts, corrected (Box 3)
  - Lodz I, typescript drafts, corrected (Box 3)
  - Lodz II, typescript drafts, corrected, 4 (Box 3)
- February 2001 Acquisition, 1984, 1990, undated; 4; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 112
  - The End of Affection, typescript screenplay, mimeograph corrected, by Rubington a.k.a. Akbar del Piombo, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Demi-tasse: The Intimate Coffee Table Book: An Investigation into the Life and Times of Akbar del Piombo, printed version, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Is God French?, collage novel, typescript, photocopy, undated; 6 (Box 4)
- April 2001 Acquisition, 1951-1980, undated; 5; 1; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 130
  Contains typescript drafts, corrected, of Rubington's writings.
  Arrangement
  Organized into two series: Writings and Other Papers.
  - Writings
    - Soup du Jour II: Orient, typescript drafts, corrected, undated; 2 (Box 5)
    - Soup du Jour: M, undated (Box 5)
    - Shorts, undated
      - The Karma Dream Man (Box 5)
      - Much to Say Who to One Another (Box 5)
      - Orpheus in the Real World/ Jarvis (Box 5)
    - Short Shots, undated
      - Zalda/Mahmoudi (Box 5)
      - The Karma Dream Man (Box 5)
      - Pot Pourri (Box 5)
      - LSD (Box 5)
      - When Poets Die the Last Day (Box 5)
      - The Last Hour (Box 5)
    - That Was a Fertile Period, undated (Box 5)
    - Stories from Scorpio, undated (Box 5)
    - The Karma Dream Man, undated (Box 5)
    - The End of Affection, typescript screenplay, corrected, by Rubington a.k.a. Akbar del Piombo, undated (Box 5)
  - Other Papers
    - University of Illinois catalog, 1955 (Box 5)
    - Clippings, 1961-1980 (Box 5)
    - Resumes, biographical information, 1980, undated (Box 5)
    - American Academy in Rome, 1951-1955 (Box 5)
- May 2001 Acquisition, 1990, undated; 6; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 134
  - Soup du Jour II: Paris, undated; 3 (Box 6)
  - Soup du Jour I: Lola, undated; 3 (Box 6)
  - Limericks, undated (Box 6)
  - Hoboken, 1990 (Box 6)
- July 2001 Acquisition, undated; 7; 1; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 175
  Contains films by Rubington. Box 15 contains the original film cans. Films have been rehoused and placed in cold storage.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 7-14 (motion picture film): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Minnetonka/Walker, (1 16mm film) (Box 7 (Cold storage))
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Hi Tension, (1 16mm film) (Box 8 (Cold storage))
  - Frabjous Day Pu, (1 16mm film) (Box 9 (Cold storage))
  - Frabjous Day Pu San Français, (1 16mm film) (Box 10 (Cold storage))
  - La Valse/The Walk, original negative, (1 16mm film) (Box 11 (Cold storage))
  - Moonglow, (1 16mm film) (Box 12 (Cold storage))
  - Moonglow [black and white?], (1 16mm film) (Box 13 (Cold storage))
  - Unidentified [black and white negative], (1 16mm film) (Box 14 (Cold storage))
  - Original film cans for 16mm films, 7 (Box 15)
- May 2001 Acquisition, undated; 8; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 183
  - Proxy F.O.O.L.S., collage novel with artwork, various drafts, 8 (Box 16)
  - Proxy F.O.O.L.S., collage novel with artwork, various drafts (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Poca Roba, typescript draft with artwork (Box 17 (Oversize))